A Finding Aid to the Reginald R. Isaacs Papers, circa 1842-1991, bulk 1928-1991, in the Archives of American Art AAA.isaaregi
Archives of American Art
- Walter Gropius Biography, circa 1800s-1991, undated; Series 13; 16 Linear feet Boxes 6-22, OV 23, MGP 1, 2, 4
  - Photographs and Illustrations for the Biography, circa 1800s-1983, undated; 13.6
    - 17: Boxehrens, Peter; Boxehrens and daughter, Petra; Karl Ernst Osthaus' house; Lehmann Department Store, Cologne, interiors designed with Behrens; Gropius and his Aunt Wiene, Chislehurst, England, 1908-1910 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - 18: Sears, Roebuck & Co., catalog, "Houses by Mail"; E. F. Hodgson, Co., Hodgson Houses, 1908 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - 19: Gropius, Janikow; Meyer, Adolf; Kleffel Starch Factory, Baumgarter (Kreis Karwitz), Janikow, with Meyer; Mahler, Alma Schindler; monument to Otto von Bismarck, Coblenz, competition entry, with Meyer, 1910-1929 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - 20: Fagus Werk, Alfeld-an-der-Leine, with Meyer (includes an original drawing of a door handle), 1910-1911 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - 21: Von Arnim House, Falkenhagen, Pomerania, with Meyer, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - 22: Storage Warehouse, Markisch, Friedland; Von Brockhausen workers' housing, Mittelfelde; Von Brockhausen conservatory, Mittelfelde; Von Borke house, Gut Golzen; Boxenzine motor railroad car, 1911-1914 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - 23: Alfeld-an-der-Leine hospital proposal with Meyer; "Eigene Scholle," Wittenberge an der Oder, with Meyer, 1912-1913 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - 24: Worker's housing for Bernburger Machine Company, Alfeld; Worker's housing, Dramburg, 1913-1914 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - 25: Werkbund Exhibition, Cologne: factory, office building, and machinery hall pavilion for Deutz Machine Factory, with Meyer, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - 26: Gropius Hohe, Mt. Aubry, Senones, Vosges; Moussey Chateau, Gropius' billet; Alma Schindler Mahler, letter to Gropius; van de Velde, Henry, 1915, 1914, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - 27: Alma Schindler Mahler Gropius; Gropius, Vonvalescence; the Oise, aftermath of battle, 1916-1918 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - 28: "Mountains for Living," project for the "Glass Chain," drawings by Gropius and Frank Moller; Weimar Bauhaus, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - 29: Birthday letters from Lyonel Feininger "Papileo" to Gropius; Hildebrandt, Lily and other students of AdolfHolzel in Dachau; Sommerfeld Andrew; Sommerfeld house, Berlin-Dahlem, and furniture; Weimar Bauhaus Director's Office; Sommefeld Factory and office building, Berlin; Sommerfeld rowhouses, Berlin, with Meyer, 1920-1952 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - 30: Monument to those killed in the Kapp Putsch designed by Gropius, 1921 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - 31: Otte house, Berlin-Zehlendorf, with Meyer; Kallenbach house, Berlin, with Meyer, 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - 32: Municipal Theater, Jena, before and after remodeling, with Meyer, 1923-1924 (Box 17, Folder 32)
      One glass plate negative housed in MGP 4.
    - 33: Klee, Paul; statement by Paul Klee; Gropius; van Doesburg, Theo, 1921, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - 34: Bauhaus cooperative housing project, Weimar; Demonstration house "am Horn", Weimar, with Georg Muche and Adolf Meyer, architects, 1922-1923 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - 35: Chicago Tribune office building competition entry, with Meyer; Rauth house, Berlin-Wohnhaus, proposal, with Meyer, 1922 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - 36: "Die Meisterrat," Oskar Schlemmer and Gropius in Opposition, sketch by Schlemmer; "Color sonatina in red," Ludwig Hirschfeld-Mack; Henri van de Velde's villa; LeCorbusier's diagram and instructions for mounting his works at the 1923 exhibition; Weimar Bauhaus mural, Herbert Bayer, 1922-1923 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    - 37: Gropius; Ise Frank; Le Corbusier, Cafe des Deux Magots, Paris; Wassily Kandinsky, J.J.P. Oud Gropius; von Klitzing Summer house, Timmendorf, proposal with Meyer; Faguswerk warehouse and service building, Alfeld-an-der-Leine, with Meyer, 1923-1924 (Box 17, Folder 37)
    - 38: Piet Mondrian letter to Gropius; Hannover Paper Factory, Alfeld-Gronau, with Meyer; Kappe storage warehouse, Alfeld-an-der-Leine, with Meyer, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - 39: Friedrich Frobel Institute, Bad Liebenstein, Thuringia, proposal; Philosophy Academy, Erlangen, proposal with Meyer, 1923-1924 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - 40: Gropius, Amalfi; Ise Gropius, Amalfi, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 40)
    - 41-45: Boxauhaus, Dessau, buildings with plans, exterior and interior views, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 41-45)
    - 46: Master's house and student housing, Bauhaus, Dessau, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 46)
    - 47: Masters and students at the Elbe River, Dessau, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 47)
    - 48: Torten housing development, Dessau, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 48)
    - 49: Friedrichshone, Bernberg, 1926-1929 (Box 17, Folder 49)
    - 50: Remodelled residence of Karl Benscheidt, Jr., Alfeld; Teachers Association building, Dresden, proposal, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 50)
    - 51: Muller factory, Kirchbraak, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 51)
    - 52: Passport photos, Gropius and Ise Gropius; Oskar Schlemmer's class, Dessau, 1925 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - 53: Two dwellings for Werkbund Housing Exhibition, the "Weissenhof," Stuttgart, and Zuckerkandl house, Jena, 1927-1928 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 54: Harnischmacher house, Mainz; Lewin house, Berlin-Zehlendorf; Hecke house, Hamburg, proposal; Molling and Co.; Jacobsthal house, 1927 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - 55: Dammerstock housing development, Karlsruhe, competition, 1927 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - 56: Total Theater, Berlin, proposal for Erwin Piscator, 1927 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - 57: Municipal Employment Office, Dessau, competition, 1927-1928 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - 58: Gropius in Copenhagen; Ostwald, Wilhelm with Gropius; Boxerlage, Hendrik with Gropius; Boxartok, Bela, and Paul Klee with Gropius, 1927 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - 59: Gropius with Manon; Manon; Meyer, Hannes, 1927-1930, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - 60: "The Dessau Bauhaus Cracks-Up," cartoon; "The Bauhaus Director in Dessau Removing the Last Ornaments from his Family," cartoon from "Simplicissimus," Munich, 1927 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - 61: Walter Gropius; Ise Gropius; "Farewell party," Sommerfeld home, Berlin; Gropius' impressions of U.S. including housing and oil rigs, Chicago; Gropius at the Grand Canyon, Arizona, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - 62: 121 Potsdamer Street, Berlin, Gropius' flat and office; Gropius' office staff, Berlin, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - 63: Mechanical Engineering School, Hagen, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - 64: Fischtalgrund Exhibition Hall, Berlin-Zehlendorf; Spandau-Haselhorst experimental housing project, Berlin, competition, 1928, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - 65: Siemensstadt housing cooperative, Berlin, 1929-1930 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - 66: "Am Lindenbaum" housing development, Frankfurt, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - 67: Aschrott Home for the Aged, Kassel, competition, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - 68: Modular furniture for the Feder Company, Berlin, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - 69: Designs for Adler Automobiles; School, Berlin-Copenick, 1929-1933 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - 70: School, Schwarzerden in der Rhon; slab block, steel construction, proposal, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - 71: Ukrainian State Theater competition, Kharkov Palace of Justice, Berlin, proposal; Palace of the Soviets, Moscow, competition, 1930, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - 72: Wannsee Shores apartments, Berlin, proposal, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - 73: Prefabricated houses for Hirsch Copper and Brass Works, Finow, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - 74: Mendelssohn Sanatorium, proposal; Schawinsky, Alexander (Xanti) with photos of Herbert Bayer, Marcel Breuer, and Walter; Gropius, 1928-1931 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - 75: Deutscher Werkbund Exhibition, Paris - Gropius with Herbert Bayer, Marcel Breuer, and Laszlo Moholy-Nagy, 1929-1930 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - 76: Gropius on skis, Davos; Palace of Justice, competition?; Nagel apartments, Nuremberg, proposal; exhibition of Gropius' works, Zurich, 1930-1931 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - 77: Stove for Frank Iron Works; "Spirit of Ascona," with Ise Gropius, Xanti Schawinsky, and Herbert Bayer; B.D.A. (Bund Deutscher Architekten) meeting, Berlin; C.I.A.M. (Congres Internationaux d'Architecture Moderne) meeting, Barcelona, including Jose Luis Sert, Le Corbusier, Cornelius van Eesteren, Gropius, and Victor Bourgeois; beach resort, Ciudad Balneira, Argentina, 1931-1932 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - 78: German Building Exhibition, Berlin; Gropius; Reichsbank, Berlin, competition; Bahner house, Klein-Machow, Berlin, 1932 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - 79: Non Ferrous Metal Exhibition, Berlin, with Joost Schmidt, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - 80: Recreation center project, Tiergarten, Berlin, competition, with Rudolf Hillebrecht; Rosa-Barcelona project; Gropius in Budapest; Xanti Schawinsky letter to Gropius, 1933-1934 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - 81: A. P. Simon project, Manchester, proposal, with Maxwell Fry, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - 82: Volta Theater Conference, Rome; Gropius passport photo; Pritchard, Jack C., sketch by Kapp; Lawn Roads flats, Hampstead, London, Wells Coates, architect; Gropius' Birthday including Gropius, Molly Pritchard, Ise, J.C. Pritchard, and Mrs. Marcrieff; Dr. Markova, Marcel Breuer, Ise, Gropius, unknown, and J.C. Pritchard, 1934-1935, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - 83: Dartington Hall cottages and theater, Totnes, Devonshire, with Maxwell Fry, 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - 84: Gropius, Manon; Manon Gropius' gravestone designed by Gropius; C.I.A.M. meeting, Amsterdam; Frank Gropius, Beate (Ati) with Ise and Hertha Frank, 1934-1936 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - 85: Film Processing Laboratory for Denham Laboratories, Oxbridge, with Maxwell Fry (includes slides), 1935 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - 86: Pioneer Health Care Center, Peckham, London, proposal (includes slides), 1935 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - 87: Impington Village College, Cambridgeshire, with Maxwell Fry, 1936-1937 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - 88: Max Ernst's depiction of Gropius as a bird in a cage (England), caricature on tile, circa 1935 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - 89: Levy house, London, with Maxwell Fry (includes slides), 1936 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - 90: Donaldson house, Shipbourne, Kent, with Maxwell Fry; farewell at Waterloo Station, London, Gropius and Ise; Gropius' horoscope drawing by Joost Schmidt (includes a slide), 1936-1937, circa 1947 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - 91: Gropius and Ise, arrival in New York; teaching of the Beaux-Arts at Harvard University, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - 92: Gropius; Ati Gropius and Gropius; Boxauhauslers at Planting Island, Massachusetts including Xanti Schawinsky, Herbert Bayer, Mary Breuer, Gropius, and Laszlo Moholy-Nagy, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - 93: Gropius house, Lincoln, Massachusetts, with Marcel Breuer, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - 94: Wheaton College Art Center, Norton, Massachusetts, with Marcel Breuer; Breuer house, Lincoln, Massachusetts; Hagerty house, Cohasset, Massachusetts with Breuer; Bauhaus Exhibition, Museum of Modern Art, New York designed by Herbert Bayer; James Ford house, Lincoln, Massachusetts with Breuer, 1937-1938 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - 95-98: Gropius, Chairman, Department of Architecture, Graduate School of Design, Harvard University including Gropius with Marcel Breuer, Joseph Hudnut, Ise, Richard Neutra, Konrad Waschsmann, and students (includes slides), circa 1938-1952 (Box 18, Folder 44-47)
    - 99: Wright, Frank Lloyd, Lincoln Massachusetts, including Marcel Breuer, Mr. and Mrs. Plant and Gropius; Gropius, "Falling Water," Pennsylvania photos including Gropius, Edgar Kaufmann and Edgar Kaufmann, Jr., 1939-1940 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 100: Frank house, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Gropius with Dahlen K. Ritchey and Breuer, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - 101: Pennsylvania Pavilion, New York World's Fair, with Breuer; Black Mountain College project, North Carolina, proposal with Breuer; Huxley, Julian with Gropius, Lincoln, Massachusetts, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - 102: Stravinsky, Igor, Lincoln, Massachusetts; Gropius, Long Island, New York; Gropius, Key West, Florida; Recreation Center, Key West, Florida with Konrad Waschmann; Aluminum City Terrace, housing project, New Kensington, Pennsylvania with Breuer; Abele house, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - 103: Ozenfant, Amedee, Lincoln, Massachusetts; Packaged House System and General Panel Corporation with Konrad Waschmann, 1941-1942 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - 104: Gropius and Colvin, Lincoln, Massachusetts; Hudnut, Joseph and Gropius, Harvard University; Michael Reese Hospital, Chicago, Illinois (Gropius - Planning Consultant), 1942, 1945-1958 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - 105: "Two Cities: Planning in North and South America," Museum of Modern Art, New York, New York including exhibition program; Church, Torreon, Mexico, proposal, with Jorge Gonzales Reyna, 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - 106: School of Design, Chicago, Illinois including Gropius, Laszlo Moholy-Nagy, and students; Howlett house, Belmont, Massachusetts, with TAC (The Architects Collaborative); Gropius' Harvard faculty meeting note regarding Joseph Hudnut, 1945-1948 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - 107: Graduate Center, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts - with TAC, 1948-1960 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - 108: C.I.A.M. meeting, London including Ernesto Rogers and Le Corbusier; Stichweh house, Hanover; Boston Back Bay Center, Boston, Massachusetts, proposal, with Pietro Belluschi, Walter Bogner, Carl Koch, Hugh Stebbins, and TAC, 1951, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - 109: Gropius, near Colorado Springs; Gropius Pine Tree, Lincoln, Massachusetts; Gropius Copper Beech Tree, Cambridge, Massachusetts; "World Tree," Harvard Graduate Center, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1938-1952 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - 110: International Advisory Panel for UNESCO headquarters building, Paris including Breuer, Gropius, Le Corbusier, Sven Markelius, Ernesto Rogers, Eero Saarinen, and others, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - 111: Gropius' 70th Birthday including John Retalliata, Gropius, Mies van der Rohe, Isaacs; Gropius Oak Tree, Chicago; Matarazzo International Grand Prize in Architecture, Sao Paulo, Brazil, including Alvar Aalto, Gropius, Ernesto Rogers, and Jose Luis Sert, 1953-1954, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - 112-113: Gropius in Japan, including Ise and others, 1954 (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
    - 114: Gropius on the Acropolis in Greece, including Ise; Adenauer, Konrad with Gropius, Harvard University, 1954-1955 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - 115-116: Pan-American World Airways Building, New York City, designed with Alex Cvijanovic and Pietro Belluschi, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 17-18)
    - 117: Interbau apartment building, Berlin Hansaviertel, with TAC, 1955-1957 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - 118: United States Embassy, Athens, with TAC, 1956-1961 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - 119: Springfield College, Massachusetts, Master Plan; Civic center, Tallahassee, Florida; Hanseatic Goethe Prize, Hamburg; "Universal" School Prototype proposal for Collier's Magazine, with TAC, 1955-1957 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - 120: Award of "Grosse Verdienst Kruez mit Stern," from the Federal Republic of Germany showing Gropius with German Embassy Attache, Franz Kraps and Gropius' granddaughter, Sarina Forberg; Sarina Forberg and Gropius, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - 121: Gropiusstadt, Britz-Buckow-Rudow, Berlin, with TAC, including Gropius at the ground breaking ceremony with Willy Brandt and others, 1956-1961 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - 122-123: University of Baghdad, master plan with TAC, 1955-1957 (Box 19, Folder 24-25)
    - 124: Taut, Max, Gropius, Hans Scharoun, and Richard Scheibe at the Akademie der Kunste, Berlin; award of the Goether Prize, Paulskirche, Frankfurt Am Main, 1961-1962 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - 125: Hillebrecht, Rudolf, Gropius, Hans Maria Wingler, Darmstadt, Berlin, Bauhaus-Archiv; Bauhaus-Archiv, Darmstadt, Berlin, with Alex Cvijanovic and TAC; Bochum University project, competition, with TAC, 1961-1968 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - 126: Dom-Romerberg, Frankfurt, competition, with TAC, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - 127: Prof. Erhard with Gropius, Selb; Rosenthal Ceramic Factory, Selb, with TAC including the building, Philip Rosenthal, Alex Cvijanovic, and others, 1963-1967 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - 128: Double school and day care center, Berlin-Buckow-Rudow, with TAC; apartment building for GEHAG, Gropiusstadt, Berlin, with TAC; apartment-office project, Toronto, with TAC, 1961-1966 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - 129: Thomas Glass Factory, Amberg, with TAC, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - 130: Park Lane Building, London, with Richard Llewelyn-Davies, John Weeks, and TAC; Gropius' lost wager: a pig-pen for Philip Rosenthal's pet pig, with TAC, 1960-1968 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - 131: China service for Rosenthal, with Louis McMillen and Katherine DeSouza; Royal Gold Medal of Royal Institute of British Architects (R.I.B.A.), including Gropius with C.H. Aslin, E. Maxwell Fry, and Sir Herbert Read, 1956-1968 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - 132: Place St. Cyrille, Quebec, proposal, with TAC; John F. Kennedy Federal Building, Boston, with N. C. Fletcher and Samuel Glaser Associates, 1961-1966 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - 133: Television Talk with Jack Cotton, Gropius, and Ise, London; Gropius' 80th Birthday, 1960, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - 134: Tower East, Shaker Heights, Ohio, with TAC, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - 135: TAC Office Building, Cambridge, Massachusetts, with TAC; Pepper Pike housing, Ohio, propsal, with TAC, 1965, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - 136: Gropius' 85th Birthday, Harvard University; German ambassador's residence, Buenos Aires, proposal, with Alex Cvijanovic, 1968-1969 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - 137: Gropius in Arizona (includes a slide); Gropius' 86th Birthday at TAC, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - 138: Gropius Exhibition, Stuttgart including Gropius with Ise, Herbert Bayer, and the exhibiton, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - 139: Portraits of Walter Gropius and others, including a group photo of architecture educators at Cranbrook Academy with Eero Saarinen, Joseph Hudnut, Leon Arnal, and Eliel Saarinen, 1930-1939 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - 140: Portraits of Walter Gropius and others including Ise Gropius, C.I.A.M. meeting Bridgewater, and Gropius in Havana, Cuba, 1940-1949 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - 141: Portraits of Walter Gropius and others, including Gropius by Hans Namuth, Max Cetto, Gropius in Lima, Peru, 1950-1954 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - 142: Portraits of Walter Gropius and others including Jose Luis Sert, and presentation of the American Institute of Architects (A.I.A.) Gold Medal to Gropius, 1955-1959 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - 143: Portraits of Walter Gropius and others, 1960-1963 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - 144: Portraits of Walter Gropius and others including Gropius' 80th Birthday with Alvar Aalto, Ise, TAC staff, and Reginald Isaacs, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - 145: Portraits of Walter Gropius and others, 1964-1967 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - 146: Portraits of others: Bayer, Herbert; Dorner, Alexander, 1929, 1940, 1957, 1959, undated (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - 147: Architectural designs by Walter Gropius and others including Peter Behrens, Le Corbusier, Adolf Loos, J.J.P. Oud, Hans Poelzig, Ludwig Mies van der Rohe, Louis Sullivan, undated (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - 148: Architectural designs by Walter Gropius and others - East Berlin, unidentified, undated (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - 149: Architectural designs by Le Corbusier including (slides) Palace of Assembly, Chandigarh, India; Sainte-Maire de La Tourette; Notre-Dame du Huat, Ronchamp; and Villa Savoye, Poissy, Paris (slides), undated (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - 150: Architectural designs by Bauhaus Faculty -Bill, Max, undated (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - 151: Architectural designs by Bauhaus Graduates, Horstmann, Edgar and Selmanagic, Selman, 1939, undated (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - 152: Architectural designs by Harvard Graduates including Department of Architecture and Regional Planning; Morse, John, undated (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - 153-156: Architectural designs by Harvard Graduates of the School of Design including Duhart, Emilio; Seidler, Harry, 1948, 1960, 1967, undated (Box 19, Folder 55-58)
    - 157: Architectural designs, unidentified, undated (Box 19, Folder 59)
    - 158-161: Works of art by Bauhaus Graduates including Ahlfeld-Heyman, Marianne; Cidor, Ruth; Driesch-Foucar, Lydia; Graeff, Werner; Lutz, Rudolf, undated (Box 19, Folder 60-63)
      (3 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 1)
    - 162: Works of Art by the Architects Collaborative (TAC), for Gropius' 83rd Birthday, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 163-164: Miscellaneous including Pergamon Allar, Berlin; Coca Castle, Spain; Church of Santa Maria Ara Coeli, Rome; Albert Medal Plaque (slides); 1709 Cambridge, 1935-1936; Megapolis, Greece (slides); Walter Gropius (slides), undated (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
      One lantern slide housed in MGP 2.
    - Oversized Photograph of Family Group, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Oversized Photograph of Unidentified Individual, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Oversized Pencil Drawing (of two men at a table), undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Oversized Plat, German Building Exposition, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Oversized Photograph of Gropius and others, Harvard Architects School, 1940 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Oversized Photograph, [Sears, Roebuck & Co. houses], undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Oversized Portraits of Gropius, 1955-1959 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Oversized Portrait of Gropius, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Oversized Portrait of Gropius, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Oversized Township Study Prepared by students in Depts. of Architecture and Regional Planning, Harvard University, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, 3 Glass negatives (Box MGP 1)
    - Glass Plate Negatives, 2 Glass negatives (Box MGP 2)
    - Lantern Slide, 1 Lantern slides (Box MGP 2)
    - Glass Plate Negative, 1 Glass negatives (Box MGP 4)
  - Printed Material, 1912-1991, undated; 13.7
    The printed material Isaacs collected as research material for the Gropius biography totals 2 linear feet. The items are mostly newspaper, journal, and magazine clippings, but there are a few bound volumes including The Architects Collaborative, TAC, edited by Herausgegeben von, Arthur Niggli Ltd., 1965, and the completed 2 volume biography by Isaacs, Walter Gropius: der Mensch und sein Werk, 1983, 1984.
    The folder of miscellaneous exhibition catalogs and announcements concerns the exhibitions "de stijl," at the Museum of Modern Art, New York, in 1961 and Hampstead in the Thirties, A Committed Decade, Camden Arts Centre, London, in 1975
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Walter Gropius, 1963-1971 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Bauhaus Faculty and Graduates, 1953-1986, undated (Box 20, Folder 5-7)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, The Bauhaus, 1961-1971 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Miscellaneous, 1961, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material for Walter Gropius Biography (in alphabetical order), undated (Box 20, Folder 10-15)
    - Printed Material for Walter Gropius Biography, 1912-1963 (Box 20, Folder 16-33)
    - Printed Material for Walter Gropius Biography, 1964-1991, undated (Box 21, Folder 1-31)
- Unprocessed Addition, 1974-1985; Series 14; 1 Linear feet Box 24
  This unprocessed addition from 1997 includes correspondence, manuscript drafts, notes, copy prints and negatives, and publishing information pertaining to Isaacs' biography of Walter Gropius.
  - Unprocessed Addition, 1974-1985 (Box 24)